longliveimagination.com 2014-05-21

# Canon U.S.A. : Privacy Statement - Your Privacy Rights

Last updated: January 1, 2014

Introduction

As a member of the Canon Inc. family of companies, Canon U.S.A., Inc. ("Canon USA") is committed to protecting your privacy. This Privacy Statement describes the information we collect from you, either online or offline, and how that information will be used. Please read this Privacy Statement carefully. Should you have any questions, please refer to the end of the Statement for information on how to contact us.

**Table Of Contents:**

  * The Information We Collect
  * How We Use Information
  * With Whom We Share Your Information
  * Our Commitment To Children's Privacy
  * Your Choices About Collection and Use of Your Information
  * Third-Party Web Sites and Interest-Based Marketing
  * User Generated Content
  * Information Security
  * Visiting Our Web Site From Outside The United States
  * Right to Change Internet Privacy Statement
  * Your California Privacy Rights

  * How To Contact Us

**_The Information We Collect_**

**Personal Information**

You may visit our web site and not provide us with any information that can identify you. But if you decide to contact Canon USA to, for example, purchase a product from us, request information about repair estimates, order a repair, open a Canon Account, register a product, download certain software or service applications, complete a survey, enter a contest or sweepstakes, submit a rebate, inquire about products you may already own, request samples of certain products or provide a product review or other feedback, we may collect information such as your name, e-mail or postal address, phone number and credit card information ("Personal Information"). We may also periodically obtain Personal Information about you from other Canon companies, business partners, service providers, and contractors acting on our behalf and add it to other information we have collected about you. Examples of such information include updated credit, delivery and address information, purchase history, and fulfillment information. 

**Non-Personal Information**

We also collect non-personal information from various sources. This information, also known as anonymous or aggregate data, is data in a form that does not permit direct association with any specific individual:

**Information collected automatically.** When you visit our web site, we collect certain information automatically. This information includes the IP address used to connect your computer to the Internet, information about your browser type and language, the date and time you are accessing our web site, and the referring web site address. It may also include technical data about the Canon products you are using.

**Use of cookies and other technologies.** We may collect information about your use of our web site through the following means:

  * _Cookies._ When you visit our web site, we may assign your computer one or more "cookies." A cookie is a small text file that contains information that can later be read by us to facilitate your access to our web site and personalize your online experience. For example, if you are a registered user of our web site, we will record your user ID in a cookie file on your computer. Also, through the use of a cookie, we may automatically collect information about your online activity on our web site, such as the web pages you visit, the links you click, and the searches you conduct. Most browsers automatically accept cookies, but you can usually modify your browser setting to decline cookies by visiting the Help portion of your browser's toolbar. If you choose to decline cookies, please note that you may not be able to sign in or use some of the interactive features offered on our web site.
  * _Other Technologies._ We may use standard Internet technology, such as web beacons (also called clear GIFs or pixel tags) and other similar technologies, to track your use of our web site. We also may include web beacons in e-mail messages, newsletters and advertisements to determine whether messages have been opened and acted upon. The information we obtain in this manner enables us to customize the services we offer and measure the overall effectiveness of our online content and the products and services we offer through the web site.
  * _Use by Third-Parties._ We may allow third-parties, including our authorized service providers, advertising agencies and marketing partners to use tracking technologies, such as cookies and web beacons, to collect non-personal information about your visits to this and other web sites. This information generally enables them to track and gauge the effectiveness of our web site and of various marketing campaigns and to serve ads about goods and services that may be of interest to you when you visit other web sites across the Internet.

**_How We Use Information_**

**In General.** We may use the information we collect about you to respond to your requests for information; to deliver the products and services you have requested; to manage your account and provide you with customer support; to provide you with information about other Canon products and promotions that may be of interest to you; to obtain feedback on our products and services; to perform research and analysis about usage and potential interest in our products, services, or content; to develop and display content and advertising tailored to your interests on our web site; to enforce our Terms and Conditions and to perform functions as otherwise described to you at the time of collection.

**Financial Information.** We may use financial information or payment method to process payment for any purchases or sales made on our web site, to protect against or identify possible fraudulent transactions, and otherwise as needed to manage our business. 

**Information From/About Friends or Family.** If you provide us with information about others, or if others give us your information, we may store that data, but it will only be used for the specific reason it was provided. Examples include providing a friend's shipping address, e-mailing a newsletter or a product description to a friend, and e-mailing friends a link to your Wish List.

**_With Whom We Share Your Information_**

Our customers are a critical component of our business and we are not in the business of selling or renting your personal information to third-parties. We are part of the Canon Inc. family of companies and may share your information with our parent company, subsidiaries, and affiliates. We also may share your information with other companies and individuals acting on our behalf to fulfill and/or ship an order, an award or rebate; to conduct surveys, contests or sweepstakes; to perform business and sales analysis; to communicate with you; collect or process payments; provide data processing or data storage processes on our behalf; or to provide a product or service you have requested. We also may periodically share your personal information with selected non-Canon companies with whom we have partnered to provide you with products and services, or whose products and services we believe you may find of interest. In addition, if you inquire about a product that Canon USA does not sell directly, we may forward your information to a Canon USA dealer, distributor or other reseller, and they may reach out to you about your product needs.

We also may share aggregated information we collect with third-parties, including service providers and marketing partners, for the purpose of conducting general business analysis. For example, we may tell our marketing partners the number of visitors to our web site and the most popular features or services accessed. This information does not contain any personal information and may be used to develop web site content and services that we hope you will find of interest.

In any event, the third-parties with whom we conduct business are obligated to use your information only to perform the service for which they are hired.

Finally, we also may share your personal information:

  * In response to a subpoena or similar investigative demand, a court order, or a request for cooperation from law enforcement or other government agency; to establish or exercise our legal rights; to defend against legal claims; or as otherwise required by law. In such cases, we may raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us.
  * When we believe disclosure is appropriate in connection with efforts to investigate, prevent, or take other action regarding illegal activity, suspected fraud or other wrongdoing; to protect and defend the rights, property or safety of our company, our users, our employees, or others; to comply with applicable law or cooperate with law enforcement; or to enforce our web site Terms and Conditions or other agreements or policies.
  * In connection with a substantial corporate transaction, such as the sale of our business, a divestiture, merger, consolidation, or asset sale, or in the unlikely event of bankruptcy.

**_Our Commitment To Children's Privacy_**

Protecting the privacy of the very young is especially important. For that reason, we never collect or maintain information from those we actually know are under 13, nor does Canon USA target its web site to children under 13. Canon USA encourages parents and guardians to spend time online with their children and to participate with them in the various interactive activities and downloadable projects that may be available on our web site from time to time.

**_Your Choices About Collection and Use of Your Information_**

If you no longer wish to receive communications from Canon USA, please click here to unsubscribe. If you wish to update your e-mail address in our records, click here to update your information.

You can choose not to provide us with certain information, but that may result in you being unable to use certain features of our web site because such information may be required in order for you to register; purchase products or services; participate in a contest, promotion, survey, or sweepstakes; ask a question; or initiate other transactions on our web site.

Some of our web sites may provide you with a choice as to whether you want to receive e-mail messages about special offers. You will be given the opportunity in any commercial e-mail that we send to you to opt out of receiving such e-mail messages in the future. Please note that we may send you other types of transactional and relationship e-mail communications, such as service announcements and administrative notices without offering you the opportunity to opt out of receiving them.

**_Third-Party Web Sites and Interest-Based Marketing_**

**Links.** There are a number of places on our web site where you may click on a link to access other web sites that do not operate under this Privacy Statement. For example, if you click on an advertisement or a third-party logo on our web site, you may be taken to a web site that we do not control. These third-party web sites may independently solicit and collect information, including personal information, from you. We recommend that you consult the privacy statements of all third-party web sites you visit by clicking on the "privacy" link typically located at the bottom of the web page you are visiting.

**Job applicants.** If you submit an application or resume online when applying for a position with our company, we may use third-party service providers to assist with the process of collection, maintenance and analysis of candidate submissions. These third-parties are not affiliated with Canon USA and they may maintain separate privacy policies that govern the transfer of your information. Should you have any questions about the privacy practices of these companies, we recommend that you contact them directly. Canon USA may retain your application for a period of time, but only for the purpose of considering your application for current or future available positions. Your applicant information may be shared with Canon Inc. and/or other Canon companies for the purpose of evaluating your qualifications for the particular position or other available positions.

**Interest-Based Marketing.** We contract with third-party advertising agencies, marketing partners and other service providers to serve advertisements when you visit our web site or other web sites across the Internet. The advertisements placed on these third-party web sites may use tracking technologies, such as cookies and web beacons, to collect anonymous information about your visits to this and other web sites. We may also share anonymous information with these companies in aggregate form and/or partner with these companies to provide interest-based advertising both on and off web sites operated by Canon USA. In either case, the purpose of the sharing is to provide advertisements about goods and services that may be of interest to you, analyzing and improving the effectiveness of ads and e-mails, and improving and enhancing our web site and its content.

The Canon USA website is not currently configured to recognize “do not track” signals sent as a header by Internet browsers. However, other settings within your browser may permit you to block cookies or other technology that enable websites to collect information that can be used to tailor advertisements to your interest. Please check your browser’s settings or consult your browser’s help information for more details.

As we describe above, to the extent that information is collected over time and across websites to help provide you with advertisements based on your interests, this information is anonymous and does not contain your Personal Information.

**_User Generated Content_**

We may provide areas on our web sites where you can, for example, post product reviews or reviews about our web site, ask or answer a question, communicate with others, and upload content (e.g. pictures, videos, audio files). Such postings, which may be administered by third-party service providers, are governed by our general Terms of Use and may also be subject to more specific terms that are integrated into that area of our web site. Service providers administering the postings may use tracking technology, such as cookies, to collect anonymous information about your posting. Additionally, such postings may appear on other web sites when searches are executed on the subject of your posting. Also, whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information on publicly-viewable web pages, that information can be collected and used by others. For example, if you post your e-mail address, you may receive unsolicited messages. We cannot control who reads your posting or what other users may do with the information you voluntarily post, so we encourage you to exercise discretion and caution with respect to your personal information.

Our web sites may also include features that involve a shared platform with third-party services while you are on our web sites. For example, we may allow you to sign in to your account on a social networking service to share your favorite Canon products or other information about Canon with friends on that service. If we offer or accommodate this kind of shared-platform or similar service, the third-party through which the service is provided, and with whom your information may be shared, will be identified by a recognizable icon. If you choose to use the service, information collected from you while you use our web site may be transmitted to the third-party that operates the service. Additionally, once that information is shared with the third-party, its use of information about you will be subject to that third-party's privacy policy. Finally, your activity on any social networking service pages that, for example, refer to Canon USA, include the Canon logo, or involve a Canon promotion, is guided by the general terms of the service operator or any specific terms for that promotion. You therefore should consult that third-party's privacy policy to understand how your information may be used and shared by the third-party.

**_Information Security_**

When you submit information to Canon USA through our web sites, you should be aware that your information is transmitted across multiple computer systems on the Internet. Although we take reasonable security measures to protect your information, data security technologies constantly are evolving. Because no method of transmitting or storing electronic data on the Internet is ever completely secure, we cannot guarantee that such information will never be accessed, used, or released in a manner that is inconsistent with this Statement.

**_Visiting Our Web Site From Outside The United States_**

This Privacy Statement is intended to cover collection of information on our web site from residents of the United States. If you are visiting our web site from outside the United States, please be aware that your information may be transferred to, stored, and processed in the United States where our servers are located and our central database is operated. The data protection and other laws of the United States and other countries might not be as comprehensive as those in your country. Please be assured that we seek to take reasonable steps to ensure that your privacy is protected. By using our services, you understand that your information may be transferred to our various facilities within and outside the United States and those third-parties who process information on our behalf, as described in this Privacy Statement.

**_Right to Change Internet Privacy Statement_**

This Statement was last updated effective January 1, 2014. Canon USA reserves the right to change this Privacy Statement at any time. If we make any material changes to this Statement, we will notify you by posting the changes on our web site. Changes will be effective immediately upon posting on the web site. Your continued use of our web site following the postings of changes to these terms means you accept these changes.

**_Your California Privacy Rights_**

California Civil Code Section 1798.83 gives California residents the right to request, from a business with whom the California resident has an established business relationship, certain information with respect to the types of personal information the business shares with third-parties for direct marketing purposes by such third-party, and the identities of the third-parties with whom the business has shared such information during the immediately preceding year. To request a copy of the information disclosure provided by Canon U.S.A., Inc. pursuant to California Civil Code Section 1798.83, please contact us at the address listed below.

**_How To Contact Us_**

Should you have questions or concerns about this Statement, please click HERE or mail your inquiry to Canon U.S.A., Inc. - Customer Privacy, ITCG Internet Marketing Division, One Canon Park, Melville, New York 11747.
